You need an agentic OS, but it's not for the reasons you think.
It's not because you need fancy dashboards like this or visual interfaces like this one,
even though I'll show you how to create them.
It's instead about building a custom system that takes the best of all the AI tools at your disposal,
whether that's GPT-6 Astra or Claude Opus 5.5 or Jev and builds it around you and your work
in a way you just can't get inside the terminal.
That is what this agentic OS does, and today I'm going to show you not only how it works,
but how you can build something like this for yourself.
And along the way, I'm going to show you how to create a fully local voice system,
how to integrate Jev as a virtually free, virtually instant model router,
how to create a customized skill backbone that is built around how you actually work in your day to day.
We'll also talk about how to use Obsidian as a memory layer that actually provides value,
and at the end, I'll even show you how you can package something like this,
not just for you, but for teammates and even sell the clients.
This is going to be all about showing you how to create an agentic OS that provides real value
beyond the visual spectacle, so let's get started.
So let's begin by talking about what an agentic OS, what a Claude OS even is.
So it is a three-layer system, and the first layer is the visual layer.
And that's what we're looking at here.
For me, this has a lot of stuff to do with my social media.
What's going on on my different accounts?
I have it hooked up to my calendar.
I can look at all my different skills and automations and run them from here.
And speaking of running it, I can run it either on Claude or Codex.
Now, this is all happening inside of my browser.
This is a web app, but there are no rules here.
This doesn't have to be a web app.
In fact, as you see here, I've ported it over to Obsidian.
This is also an Obsidian plugin that just like you saw can run on Claude or Codex.
But I get all the advantages of being inside the Obsidian desktop app.
I still have access to a terminal here.
I can click on any of these buttons, which are linked to different skills and automations.
I have different tabs that dive deeper into what's going on with my audience,
what's going on in AI in general, right?
I have a whole research tab that takes a look at like the GitHub trending,
outliers on YouTube, as well as things like hacker news.
The big thing with the visual side is this is ultimately 100% custom.
And you can edit this so it makes sense for you and your work or your team's work or your client's work.
Now, the second layer is the memory system.
And for that, I use Obsidian.
And the value here is not these knowledge graphs.
Like these knowledge graphs look cool, but that's about where the functionality ends
because this is not a rag system.
What the memory layer is really about is creating a file and folder structure
that makes sense for you, the human being, and for your AIOS,
so that you can get answers quickly and accurately,
even when we're talking about thousands and thousands of thousands of files.
And this is going to be based on the Carpathi Obsidian rag system.
I mean, we will dive into that in much more detail later.
And last but not least, for the third layer, we have the skill architecture.
This is the backbone of everything we do.
If you get nothing else from this video,
if you ignore the memory layer stuff,
if you ignore the visual layer stuff,
I want you to listen to this section when we dive into it in more detail.
And that is, how do we go from somebody who just uses AI to sort of help us
in our day-to-day task and offload virtually all of it to AI?
In a way that makes sense.
Because you have things you do every single day, week to week,
in your life, in your business,
that we should not only be turning into skills,
but then turning into automations.
And from those automations and from those skills,
we get certain deliverables and outputs.
Those deliverables and outputs are what is fed back into the AIOS.
All the reports you see here, all these graphics,
all of these are driven by the different skills we run.
So not only understanding that in a theoretical sense,
but having the practical know-how of how to create something like this from scratch
is what we're going to talk about.
But before we do that, a quick word from today's sponsor, me.
So inside of Chase AI Plus,
you not only can get my exact Cloud OS setup,
but you also get access to my Cloud Code and Codex Masterclass.
And these are the best and easiest way to go from zero to AI Dev
no matter your technical background.
We focus on real use cases.
It gets updated every single week.
So if you want to get more serious about this stuff,
definitely check us out.
There is a link to it down in the pinned comment.
So the Cloud OS has three layers, visual memory and skills.
But how does this thing actually work?
How do all these pieces come together?
Well, let's go through the architecture.
So let's do some examples.
So let's say I tell my Cloud OS,
which also works with voice.
Go ahead and bring up the morning until brief.
It instantly brings it up.
But if I say something like
what was the biggest news in AI today.
From today's morning brief,
a model that can't write a sentence
is beating models that can.
Jev from type say for I went into early access step 15.
We get a response like that and I cut it off.
But now if I ask you for a more complex task,
something like,
can you create me some sort of report or explainer
that kind of illustrates the difference between
Jev, that new AI system everyone's talking about
and your standard large language models
like Babel or Astra.
Okay, I'll get to work.
It'll do something like that.
You will see with this more complex task,
it actually pulled up the terminal.
So what was actually going on under the hood there?
And why did I show three different seemingly random examples?
Well, it sort of illustrates how this AIOS routes
your different requests to different models,
depending on the nature of your task.
And this is where stuff like Jev kind of comes into play,
which we see right here.
So let's focus on that third example
where I asked our Cloud OS,
hey, come with like this visual explainer
sort of illustrating the difference between Jev
and stuff like Babel.
Well, we started over here.
I simply gave it an audio request.
Now, this then went to our Obsidian plugin,
but this just as easily could have gone to our Jarvis hood.
Everything you just saw in that Obsidian plugin
also works exactly the same here.
This also is able to pull up a terminal.
That request then went to the bridge.
And the bridge does two things.
One, it takes our request
and it records all this inside of Obsidian.
Two, it then starts engaging our local voice system.
So all that speech you heard,
all the transcription, all the actual audio,
it's done locally on your machine.
So we use an open source program called Whisper,
which essentially acts as the ears of our model.
So when I said, hey, give me that explainer,
you know, Jev versus the LLMs,
it took the audio and it transcribed that into text using Whisper.
Now the audio you heard back with that sort of like Jarvis voice,
that also was a local model.
That was Kokoro, totally open source.
You could change that voice to be whatever you want.
That transcription then got sent to Jev.
And we'll do a little Jev explainer here in a second.
Jev is amazing when it acts as a classifier.
And what we want to do with Jev
is we want it to sort our requests.
And there's really three tiers of requests we can handle.
Their tier number one are for extremely simple requests
that we want pretty much instant responses to.
So when I asked it to bring up
that morning report, that morning,
until brief, this was a tier one request that Jev classified.
AI isn't even brought into the system.
If it's tier one, which is why it's able to be so fast,
we're talking about hundreds of a millisecond
to bring up these things.
And this could be something, like you saw,
I say, bring up a report
or these didn't even be commands inside of Obsidian itself,
where I say, like, hey, bring up the terminal
or something to that effect.
Then we have tier number two.
These are for non complex tasks,
but they aren't so simple that we put it into tier one.
So when I asked it something like,
hey, what was the biggest news in AI today?
I want some thinking involved.
So Jev then calls on the smallest models available to us.
This is Haiku or Luna,
depending on if I'm using the astroversion
or the cloud code version.
This is cheap, this is fast.
And if you really wanted to go into a full local setup,
you could swap these out for something
that's just running on your machine.
And then third, we have more complex real work,
which is what you saw when I asked it to create that explainer.
This is actually going to then pull up cloud code
or codex inside of your terminal, like you just saw.
This gives you the ability, if you're inside,
whether it's the Obsidian plugin or the web app,
to actually interact with the terminal in those spaces
if you want to.
So the idea is your tasks require different models
and Jev is really, really good at classifying them appropriately.
From there, all the deliverables, all the conversations,
everything you do with your AIOS is then logged back in Obsidian.
Now a real quick explanation for why we have Jev in there.
If you're not familiar with how Jev works,
because it's still new to a lot of people.
And unfortunately, a lot of sort of the discourse around it
is kind of confusing because it's an AI system,
but it's not an LLM, but people are saying it's a replacement
in some cases for cloud code or codex,
which is sort of true in certain situations,
but in general, it's not true whatsoever.
So this is like the 90 second explanation for Jev
and why it makes sense in our AIOS.
So the big thing with Jev is it allows you
to ask this AI model fuzzy questions
and get specific numbers in response,
get probabilities in response.
So here's an example.
Imagine you were using this in some sort of customer service
situation, and you have a customer that says,
I canceled my subscription last month,
but you charge me again, and you want to know
which team should handle this.
So normally, if we sent this to large language models
and they can handle this just fine,
it would say something like,
hey, this is a billing issue route to stick to the billing.
And that would be the correct answer.
Jev also does something similar,
but it doesn't give us a sentence in response.
There's no back and forth chat with Jev.
It instead gives us the probability
that there's a 92% chance this should go to billing,
which is also the correct answer.
So if we both get the correct answers,
why the heck should we care?
Well, we should care because Jev does this
extremely quickly and way cheaper.
We're talking like 200x, like faster and cheaper.
That's why we love Jev.
Cheap, fast, perfect for these situations
where you're handling what should I do in this scenario,
where there are predefined choices.
Like in our model routing scenario, right?
What are the predefined choices?
One, two, three.
Could I put Hiku here?
Could I put Lunar here?
Sure, but there's no point in doing that anymore
with Jev, which is why it's been integrated.
So that is how all of this works
from an architecture point of view.
Now, let's dive a little bit deeper into each of those three layers,
the visual, the memory, and the skills,
so you understand how you could create something like this on your own.
So let's go from the ground up,
beginning with the skill backbone.
This is the most important thing of the entire video.
And if you do nothing else,
what I'm about to show you here,
you're going to be ahead of like 99% of the people
who use Cloud Code or Codex.
Now, the idea is simple.
We are going to take all the tasks you do in your day-to-day
in your week-to-week, whether it's in your personal life
or your business and turn them into skills.
And if it makes sense, turn those skills into automations.
The value of doing that seems obvious
yet most people don't do that at all.
They do it with a few of the things they do in their day-to-day
and they certainly don't systematically go
through everything they do and break it down in this manner.
Because while this looks kind of crazy,
you probably have something similar.
If it was actually written out,
you do things related to productivity research.
Maybe it's not content in a community,
but you certainly have stuff related to clients and sales and finance
in some manner in your business life.
So why haven't we codified this into something
Cloud can help us with?
And the answer is, it just seems like too much damn work.
It seems like it would take too much time
and you don't even know where to begin.
Well, luckily, creating something like this,
breaking them all down to skills is actually relatively easy.
And there's just two things you have to do.
The first thing we're going to do is have your AI system
of choice, simply look at your logs.
Cloud Code and Codex keep a written history
of every single conversation you have with it
over the last 30 plus days.
So instead of us guessing about how Cloud or Codex
should help us in our day to day,
why don't we just have them look at how we actually use them
in reality and ask, hey, based on everything
I've done over the last 30 days,
are there any skills we could create?
That is literally the entirety of the prompt
you have to give it.
There's no special things, no crazy sort of workflow.
It's literally just, look at how I've used you
for the last 30 days, can we turn those into skills?
The second thing we are going to do is we are going to
sort of just take that idea a step further.
And instead of giving it a log,
we are just going to sit in front of Cloud Code,
sit in front of Codex, open up our microphone,
and you are going to talk nonstop for like 10 to 20 minutes.
And also going to do is you are going to explain
what you do in your day to day or your week to week.
After you dump all that information into Cloud,
and it doesn't have to be coherent.
Again, stream of consciousness.
It can get through your inability to talk correctly.
You are then going to ask it,
hey, based on everything I just told you,
what are some ways where we could create some skills
or automations to take some work off my plate?
How could we take all these tasks I've talked about
and give them to you this AI system to execute in my step?
Simply by doing that.
And neither of these scenarios require you
to have the answers beforehand.
You don't have to know what you want to turn into skills.
We'll get you pretty much 90% of the way here
of creating these skills that will make your life
infinitely better.
Now, the question of which one should be turned into automation
should be relatively straightforward.
And when it comes to turning them into automations,
yes, simply ask Cloud Codex to do that.
We can always do that manually through things like routines
or schedule tasks inside of Codex,
but these systems also have the ability to turn those into
automations that are triggered by your machine itself.
So we have a lot of flexibility here.
And again, like so many of these things,
you don't even have to have the answer
when you walk into the space.
You just have to ask Cloud or Codex to do it.
Now, how does this whole skill backbone tie
into the AIOS at large?
Well, like I talked about earlier,
the idea is we've created all these systems
with the skills and with the automations
to create things for us.
Many times they are going to be reports
and they're going to be deliverables.
Instead of having them spread in a million different places,
why don't we just consolidate them into one place?
This is where a lot of the value from the dashboard
in the visual side is actually harnessed.
For me, that's metrics.
That's a look at my schedule.
That's breaking it down into tasks.
That's the morning headlines.
That's audience metrics.
That's deeper research into things that are relevant for me.
Again, this has to be 100% customized
because you're not going to care about your YouTube subs, right?
But you undoubtedly have a lot of metrics
and on a lot of deliverables that you would like
all in one place that are easy to access
and ask questions about.
And that sort of thing can be a little bit difficult to do
even inside of the desktop applications
and definitely kind of a pain inside of the terminal.
Even if you want to argue about the value
of having that all in one sort of visual dashboard
that you can customize,
I don't think there's any argument about creating
some sort of skill backbone in your greater
cloud or codex ecosystem like this.
Now let's talk about the second layer of our system
which is the obsidian memory system.
When we talk about the high level architecture,
you could tell everything kind of touches this layer,
whatever goes in, whatever comes out,
gets recorded inside of our vault.
Now if we've never used obsidian before,
it is a completely free, simple to use desktop application
that gives you insights into your Markdown files
essentially helps with organization.
Now obsidian and things like cloud coding codex
are often used together to create
what is called a second brain.
And the second brain is the idea
that there's all these files and folders
that have to do with you or your business.
We put them in these series of files
that we have called the obsidian vault.
We run cloud code inside of those folders
and it has access to all this information about us.
Now this obsidian second brain has kind of gotten a bad rap
as of late because people have sort of over hyped
what it is obsidian does in this structure
and like what the second brain even means.
The reality is obsidian isn't giving cloud
codex any sort of like magic upgrade.
Just because this AIOS system uses obsidian,
that doesn't mean it gets like a better memory jump
or remembers things better.
That's not what obsidian does.
The obsidian desktop app just makes it very easy
to navigate those files and folders
that we have designated the vault.
And that's a subtle but important difference
because it means the power of an obsidian
second brain, the power of bringing obsidian
in the memory layer is not an obsidian itself.
The power of the system depends 100%
on simply how you organize your files and folders.
Right, if I just have one folder called the vault
and I put 10 million just random files
and there's one folder and it's completely unorganized,
but it's obsidian does that help me at all?
The answer is no, absolutely not.
So what we have to do is we need to set up
some sort of folder structure that makes sense.
And that's what you see here.
This all comes from Carpathi.
Carpathi is an AI researcher who works within
thropic now I believe and he sort of coined
this structure with obsidian cloud code
and this like obsidian rag idea.
And the idea is relatively simple.
You have this folder that you have designated
as the vault in your system where everything's going
to live just a folder on your computer.
Underneath that folder, we have three subfolders.
We have raw, we have wiki and we have outputs.
And the idea is raw data goes in the raw folder.
The wiki, folks of folder is where we sort of organize
that raw data and create like Wikipedia style articles
about them and then three is the outputs.
You know, let's say I wanted to make a slide deck
about something that was a wikipedia article.
So for example, let's say I wanted our AIOS
to find information about AI agents, right?
Do a bunch of research on AI agents.
So it does that and it creates a bunch of information
or downloads a bunch of information about AI agents
which goes in the raw folder.
Then let's imagine we have this AI agents folder
in the raw section and I want to turn it
into some sort of organized data.
Well, then it creates an AI agent subfolder down here
with all the information about AI agents
including things about autonomous coding
and tool use patterns.
And then let's say I told our cloud OS
create a PowerPoint slide deck about this.
Well, then it makes the AI agents slide deck, okay?
And that would go into the outputs.
Simple enough, that's sort of the idea.
And the cell here is that because it's set up in this way
where it's very organized and I know where everything goes
when I ask, Claude, something about anything
that's inside of my vault, it has a clear map,
a clear path of where to find that information.
So it finds it quickly and it finds it efficiently.
You know, it doesn't have to go through 10 million
folders and subfolders to get there.
There's a clear path.
And the other side of the equation is because it's organized
and that way it's easy for me, the human being
to find it if I want to.
So with that being said, how should you set up
your folder system with your AIOS, your Claude OS
inside of a vault?
Does it have to be like this, where it's raw,
where it's wiki, where it's outputs?
The answer's absolutely not.
You can kind of set it up any way you want to.
It just needs to be organized in some manner that makes sense
so that you, the human being, can navigate it
and Claude or Codex can navigate it.
Now, like so many of these things,
you don't need to have the answer.
It is as simple as telling your AIOS,
hey, this is the folder I'm using as my vault,
help me come up with some sort of organizational structure.
And it will map it out and move files and folders
as it sees fit.
The only other thing I would add to this is
in whatever folder you designate as the vault,
I highly suggest in whether it's a Claude.md or Agents.md,
you tell it what the vault structure looks like.
So you give it instructions of how to add new files
and content to your system.
So it never kind of gets out of whack or drifts.
And that's really all there is to the memory layer.
It just needs to be structured.
It just needs to be organized.
It just needs to make sense for you.
And lastly, we have the visual piece,
which we've kind of already hit on a lot here,
where the big cell for the visual piece
is all these skills have deliverables.
We have a bunch of metrics that you need to be in charge of.
And we're going to put them all in one dashboard
that we customize.
A lot of the value of sort of these custom dashboard setups
as well, though, is seen when we bring different team members
and clients into the equation.
Because there definitely is a subset of people watching
that's really like, hey, I could probably
generate something like this myself,
even if it's some like, you know,
mashed up thing inside of the desktop app.
Why would I need to do this?
Well, if you're someone who's working with team members,
or you're someone who wants to bring this to clients,
it's not as easy to bring something
you've built inside the terminal specifically to them.
On the other hand, I can create something like this
that is custom made for anybody
and set it up extremely easily.
On top of that, I can even pour in a lot of my workflows,
a lot of my skills, a lot of my automations.
And if I put them inside of the dashboard,
like you see here, where they are simply
a button one person has to press,
well, the way this works is in the background,
it's simply calling a headless version
of Cloud Coder Codex to execute those tasks.
So I could have someone sit in this chair right here
in front of my dashboard,
whether this is the city and plugin,
or the web app version,
and I can start having them just running all sorts of skills
that do a lot of work.
And they're pretty much harnessing 90, 95% of the power
of Cloud Coder Codex without even knowing how to open it up.
So on top of all the information consolidation,
when we talk about selling this
and bringing other members of our team into the fold,
the visual dashboard can actually help them ate on,
which can't be undersold even if you're someone
who's technical enough to kind of do this on your own.
And a lot of that has to do with the custom nature of it.
This is not a one size fits all thing,
which is why it's so powerful.
No matter what you need to be listed here,
no matter what you need access to all in one place,
you can build it that way.
So that's the rundown on this Cloud OS.
I hope I was able to give you a better understanding
of how you could build something like this for yourself.
If you want to get my exact setup,
whether it's the web app version
or the city and plugin,
you can find that inside of Chase AI Plus.
I'll put a link to that down in the description.
But besides that, I'll see you around.